[Music]
hi everyone this is Ravi welcome to
trient tasa Advanced Training as you all
know I already published 65 YouTube
videos covering beginners level
intermediate level and advanced level
Concepts from couple of videos onwards
I've started teaching you the real time
scenarios where you might encounter
different types of obstacles and how can
you solve those obstacles while
automating your test cases by using
tricentis TSA please do subscribe to the
channel click on Bell icon you'll
receive notifications whenever I publish
more videos don't forget to like and
share the video thank
you this is our lesson 66 in terms of
overall trient task Advanced Training
and this is our obstacle 24 in terms of
real time
scenarios so in this real time scenario
we're going to solve an
obstacle where you need
to pass the click
method in trient tasa but while passing
the click method you need to use the
Escape values so that you can input the
string as it is in the edit box instead
of per performing click
method so now let us see in detail what
is the obstacle that we need to solve
for so this is our obstacle list and our
obstacle name is escape and which is
categorized as easy let's go for
it it says input the value open curly
braces click and close curly braces into
the text box that means you need to
Simply
enter open curly braces click close
curly braces so once you enter that
entire
text or string that means you solve this
problem whenever
you provide this keyword as an input in
tasa tasa understands that you're
actually clicking on this edit box so if
you pass this key in tasa as an input
value then it's going to Simply come
here and click on this box so then how
can I enter this text in this edit Box
by escaping click method so that's what
we are going to see let us go to
Tria let us go to
trasa as usual we are going to scan the
objects pertaining to this obstacle
under obstacles folder right click
can
application and this is my application
select the application click on
scan and here I just need to capture
this text box result
text select this and make sure this
object is uniquely identified yes this
is uniquely identified now let us name
the obstru
module as obstacle
name copy and name this
obst and name this module as obstacle
name and save
it and close xcam so let's go back to
trient tasa and you can see here this is
your new module that we scan it should
has it should have result text so now
let us come to the left part of test
case blue section so let us right click
on this obstacles test case folder as
usual I'm going to create a new test
case here and name this as the obstacle
name and then double click on this now
to automate the test case we are going
to Simply drag the module and drop onto
test
case and here so what is the obstacle I
need to pass the
value open curly Braes click close curly
Braes into this text box generally what
we do to enter any value let's say
username if I provide this username
let's say username usern name if I pass
this value as username if I run this
what it does it's going to enter
username see it entered username
but our automation challenge is not that
we need to
pass open curly
braces click close curly braces if I
pass this particular key and if I run
this is it going to type open curly
braces click close curly braces
no see it is just going there and it is
performing click operation instead of
enter in the text or string so how can I
solve this problem now so there are two
ways one is you can simply right click
on this and you can use Escape Value
method as soon as I enter this Escape
value see it is taking as a
string by using double Cotes at
beginning of this string and at end of
the string I go
here just specify the double codes here
that means it's going to escape the
keyword open is going to escape the
click
operation and it considers as a string
input value so whenever you right click
and then select Escape value it's going
to escape the keyword method click
operation and it considers as a string
now I would like to run this particular
test case right click so before run I
would like to change the work state as
completed save the test case right click
and run in
scratchbook see your automation problem
is solved it entered this string entire
string open curly braces click and close
curly braces instead of Click operation
so this is how you can solve the problem
by using Escape Value
method if you have any queries leave
your queries in the comment box I'll try
to respond to your queries hope you all
understand the concept of this real time
scenario where we solve an obstacle by
using the Escape values concept
while performing click method in
tricentis tasa please do subscribe to
the channel click on Bell icon you'll
receive notifications whenever I publish
more videos don't forget to like and
share the video thank you
[Music]